<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chang-Yu Chang</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chang-Yu Chang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Run R script on HPC</title>
      <link>/post/run-r-script-on-hpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/run-r-script-on-hpc/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to run simulation about my migration project on Yale HPC (high performance cluster). After spending a day working on how to do it, I think it’s probably a good time to take a note and dust off my website. This post has the following sections:
 Run R on HPC  Load R from module Install package Run R script with arguments in command line  Run R in batch mode  Node, core, and other jargons Submit the batch job Pipeline   I am not going to go through how to access HPC, because the cluster maintainer already has the user guide, like this provided by Yale Center for Research Computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Domain and Commenting</title>
      <link>/post/customized-domain-and-commenting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/customized-domain-and-commenting/</guid>
      <description>Custom domain
 Commenting plug-in
  A quick update about new functions of this website. Two slight changes I have made: relocate the website to a customized domain, and enable the commenting function.
In case you want to know how this website was intially built, I wrote a guide. It’s a simple guide that contains other well-written tutorials and some caveats I’ve encounterd.
Custom domain Again, I found myself struggling with the terms for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Birthday Problem: Rcpp</title>
      <link>/post/generalized-birthday-problem-rcpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generalized-birthday-problem-rcpp/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I tried to use some algorithms to speed up simulation. Now in this post, I will introduce a pretty powerful package Rcpp, which has the potential to fundementally change the way you do simulation if you want to employ a time-consuming simulation in R. Let’s finish this project!
 Rcpp
 Generalized birthday problem
 GeneralBirthdayProblem Package
  Rcpp Rcpp is basically a package that incorporates C++ code in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Birthday Problem</title>
      <link>/post/generalized-birthday-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generalized-birthday-problem/</guid>
      <description>This tiny project comes from the coding class I am taking this semester. The simplest birthday problem is as followed: how many people should be in a room such that the probability of a birthday shared by at least two persons is just above 0.5? I found this problem is very interesting. Throughout the process dealing this problem, some powerful R packages and essential coding skills are incorporated for more efficient simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build up this website?</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-build-up-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-build-up-this-website/</guid>
      <description>Intro Tutorials Caveats I have jumped in  Intro The first (meaningful) post for this new website! After searching for many blog managers, I finally found out a cool and nice way to generate a good-looking website. The whole website is built under a R package blogdown, which is based on another pretty handy package rmarkdown that helps you markdown pdf or html file in Rstudio. blogdown employs a site generator called Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website!</title>
      <link>/post/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Test how to post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website!</title>
      <link>/post/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Test how to post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>